Hello everyone and welcome back
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
And my name is Katherine and we've
got a special announcement to make today.
That's right, this is lesson number 200.
So good job EnglishPod, we have
over 200 lessons already in our library.
So that's like enough for like six
months of continuous learning I think.
But the lessons keep coming
and they keep getting better.
So of course you
should continue to listen
to us, we just thought we would mention
that today is the special number 200.
Exactly.
And because it's a special
number, we're going
to talk about a very
laid back topic, but
very interesting nonetheless,
we're talking about junk food.
You might argue that
it's actually too laid back.
And it's the cause of many problems
in America and other places in the world.
Junk food is unhealthy food.
So let's take a listen to
today's dialogue and we'll
be back in a moment to
talk about what's going on.
Sure.
How about we go home and
prepare a couple of sandwiches?
Nah, let's go to burger and fries.
What you ever do is have unhealthy fast
food, pizza, fries, burgers and hot dogs.
You have to start eating better.
What are you talking about?
I have salads sometimes.
Yeah, right.
I'm serious.
You should also cut down
on your sugar intake as well.
You drink carbonated drinks
that are high and fructose syrup.
It's really not healthy.
Fine.
I'll start drinking water and having
home cooked meals that are low and fat.
Are you happy now?
It's a stop, but I'll be happy when
I see you stick to your promise.
Alright, we're back.
So let's take a look
at some of the great
words and phrases all about junk
food now in language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Mmm.
My favorite.
The stuff makes me hungry.
But it's not very good for you.
It's not.
It's terrible.
And especially his favorite
food was burger and fries.
Oh, had it for dinner last night.
Really?
Yeah, burger and fries.
Yeah, maybe.
Well, it's not very healthy and
there's a great way to describe this.
The word is unhealthy.
Alright, so yes, as you
say, it's very unhealthy.
Well, yeah, because you get fat, they're
very high in calories, so it's unhealthy.
So that means it's not good for you.
That's right.
So just a reminder in
English, when we hear
the word unhealthy or
unhappy, this means not healthy.
That's right.
One is a prefix that means not.
Mm-hmm.
Okay, and talking about unhealthy food,
in general, what are we talking about?
We're talking about fast food.
Okay, so this might require a story.
What is the meaning behind fast
food, as opposed to slow food?
Because there is no slow food, right?
I think now they have it in like
France or something like that.
They talk about slow food.
But anyways, fast food is
food as prepared very quickly.
So you go, you order
in two or three minutes,
you have your entire
order ready to go.
Okay, so maybe this
is the food that I could
get at McDonald's or
Burger King where they
make it very, very
quickly and I can go home
or I can go to the office
with my food ready.
Exactly.
So fast food, very popular among countries,
very popular nowadays among busy people who
have no time to sit down at a restaurant
or eat or sit down and have a proper lunch.
Fast food.
And one of the important drinks at a
fast food restaurant is a carbonated drink.
So this carbonated, what does this mean?
This is actually the fancy
word for soda or for fizzy drink.
Fizzy, okay, so something
that's carbonated has bubbles.
Yeah, it has bubbles.
For example, a lot of
Europeans drink carbonated
water, that means
water with bubbles in
it.
That's right.
Really the bubbles are
caused because the drink
has a high concentration of
a certain gas, such as carbon.
So that's why it has all these bubbles
in its fizzy, like Coca-Cola for example.
Right, Coca-Cola or Sprite,
these are carbonated drinks.
Very good.
So you have carbonated water
and you have carbonated soda.
What is the thing that
makes soda different?
What is it that makes soda taste so good?
It's sweet and the ingredient that
makes it sweet is called fructose syrup.
Filled toast syrup is essentially sugar.
Yeah, and it comes
from corn, I believe, right?
That's right.
So you can also hear
the name corn syrup and
this is a sweet syrup
that comes from corn
that makes drinks like Sprite
and Coca-Cola tastes so good.
It's also very unhealthy for you.
Yes, because it has a lot of calories.
So that is one of the
main ingredients in soda.
Now you know, you have fructose syrup.
All right.
So that's all we've got
for language takeaway.
Let's take another
listen to today's dialogue.
We'll be back in a second.
I'm hungry.
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
Sure.
How about we go home and
prepare a couple of sandwiches?
Nah, let's go to burger and fries.
What you ever do is have unhealthy fast
food, pizza, fries, burgers and hot dogs.
You have to start eating better.
What are you talking about?
I have salads sometimes.
Yeah, right.
I'm serious.
You should also cut down
on your sugar intake as well.
You drink carbonated drinks
at a high and fructose syrup.
It's really not healthy.
Fine.
I'll start drinking water and having
home cooked meals that are low and fat.
Are you happy now?
It's a start.
But I'll be happy when I
see you stick to your promise.
All right.
We're back.
So now we have a couple of great
phrases that we heard along the dialogue.
So let's take a look at
those now in fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right.
So starting off, this
is a very interesting
phrase because we saw
it in the first sentence.
And it says, let's go grab a bite to eat.
Let's grab a bite to eat.
So to grab is to hold
something with your hand.
OK, to do it quickly.
He grabbed my arm.
So to grab a bite to
eat, a bite is a small taste.
We're going to have a quick meal.
So after work, you want
to go grab a bite to eat?
That means let's go have
something to eat quickly.
Yeah, I'll be there soon.
Let me just grab a bite to eat.
So bite is a little bit.
It's a small amount of food.
Now for our next phrase,
it's very important because I've
noticed that a lot of our English learners
make the mistake of using this phrase.
It's how about-- How
about-- so in today's dialogue,
the phrase is, how about we go home
and prepare a couple of sandwiches?
So how about is used as a suggestion is,
how do you feel or what
do you think of going
home and preparing a
couple of sandwiches?
So another way to say this is, why don't
we go home and prepare some sandwiches?
Exactly.
But commonly, English learners
make the mistake of using
how about, as a way of
saying, how was it or how is it?
So for example, how about
your weekend, wrong, OK?
So how was your weekend?
Exactly.
So how about is usually used
when we make a suggestion?
How about we go see a movie on Saturday?
Or how about we go to my
parents' house for Christmas this year?
Or, finally, how about you get another job
so that we can have more money
to spend on going out to eat?
Very good.
So how about these are all suggestions?
Why don't you get another job?
Why don't we go to our
parents' house for Christmas?
So you can't say, how about your weekend?
You say, how was your weekend?
So there's a big difference there.
Very good.
So make sure to stay away from
that typical mistake using how about.
Now, moving on, we were talking
about fast food and how it's bad for you.
And she said, you know what?
You should also cut
down on your sugar intake.
So to cut down, that's a phrasal verb.
That's right.
Cut down.
So that means to decrease.
I'm trying to cut down on
the amount of soda that I drink.
Or I'm trying to cut down on
how much I spend on the weekends.
OK.
So to cut down means
to decrease or to lessen.
Very good.
And for our last phrase, the whole thing
that we're talking about in one of the
favorite meals for everyone, burger and fries.
OK.
So this is one of many
combinations for meals.
You can have burger and fries,
which is a hamburger and french fries.
So oftentimes you say, hey,
let's go grab a burger and fries.
Yeah.
Another combination, especially
England, is fish and chips.
Yeah, fish and chips.
Fish would be a fried fish sandwich
and chips would be french fries as well.
That's right.
So in actually in England,
they call french fries.
They call them chips.
So if you're confused by
the word chips or potato chips
and french fries, these are
different things in different places.
But if you're talking to
an American, french fries
is the way to go.
Or for a while, they
were called freedom fries.
Well, we don't need to talk about that.
We can talk about that in a later lesson.
But for now, the phrase
is burger and fries.
All right, so let's listen to our
dialogue for the very last time.
I'm hungry.
Let's go grab a bite to eat.
Sure.
How about we go home and
prepare a couple of sandwiches?
Nah, let's go to burger and fries.
What do you ever do
is have unhealthy, fast
food, pizza, fries,
burgers, and hot dogs?
You have to start eating better.
What are you talking about?
I have salads sometimes.
Yeah, right.
I'm serious, you should also cut
down on your sugar intake as well.
You drink carbonated drinks
that are high and fructose syrup.
It's really not healthy.
Fine.
I'll start drinking water and having
home cooked meals that are low and fat.
Are you happy now?
It's a stop, but I'll be happy when
I see you stick to your promise.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
We are back, Marco.
You're laughing.
I know you like junk food.
What's your favorite junk food of all time?
Actually, I am a big,
big fan of fried chicken.
I love fried chicken.
Yummy.
It's-- I don't know, I think
it's really greasy and oily
and it's very, very
bad, but I can't help it.
It's very good.
You can buy bags of it in America.
I know.
Get like a pound bag fried chicken.
You buy it by the pound in America, right?
Yep, you pay-- you pay
for how much it weighs.
Wow, that's amazing.
I actually really enjoyed, but places
like Kentucky Fried Chicken, they're
too expensive for fried chicken.
Yeah, you don't
necessarily want to go there.
There's other places that are a lot more
maybe traditional that are pretty good.
How about you?
What is your favorite junk food?
Chicago style hot dog and french fries.
Like a-- when you go to see a
baseball game, you get a hot dog.
But Chicago style is good.
It's not too much stuff on it.
You have a poppy seed bun.
So it's a bun, a piece of
bread, with some seeds on it,
and a lot of mustard
and ketchup and onions.
I really enjoy hot dogs, but the one thing
that I cannot have on a
hot dog is mustard or relish.
Oh, my gosh.
Those are the two best things.
OK, I can't talk to you anymore.
Well, tell us what your
favorite junk food is.
And tell Marco that he's
crazy if he doesn't like mustard.
Our website is EnglishPod.com.
Ask us questions as well.
We're happy to answer them.
Until next time, bye, everyone.
[MUSIC PLAYING]
[BLANK_AUDIO]